JASON F. FIERST

40 Rowley St. Apt 9 Rochester, NY 14607 M: (414) 324-4013 jason.fierst@gmail.com

PROFILE: Self-motivated and result-oriented professional with specialized skills in community, personnel, operational and administrative management. Experienced in planning and implementation of operations, training, logistics and travel for mid- to large-sized staff and or residents.

EDUCATION & TRAINING:

Rochester Institute of Technology, Rochester, New York

M.F.A. Furniture design and woodworking, currently enrolled

Eastern Michigan University, Ypsilanti, Michigan

B.F.A. Sculpture, Interior Design, 128 Credit Hours, 1998

L'Anse Creuse High School, Harrison TWP, Michigan

Concentration in fine art and design, 1991

College of Creative Studies, Detroit, Michigan

Pre-college program in art and design, 1990

U.S. Army, Armor Officer Course, Fort Knox, Kentucky, 2002

Major course work in risk management, administrative and personnel actions, maintenance management and property accountability

U.S. Army, Officer Candidate School, Fort Benning, Georgia, 2002

Major coursework in leadership, personnel, management and communications

Pacific Crest Outward Bound School, High Sierra, California, 1998

Course work in team-building, search and rescue, and group dynamics.

WORK EXPERIENCE:

Service Manager

Erik's Bike Shop, Madison, WI, 2009- 2012

Manage the service department to include scheduling, inventories, training, clinics and event support. Provide high level of mechanical and customer service. Liaison between corporate headquarters and manufacturers to include purchasing and warranty.

Americorp Volunteer

Camphill Village Minnesota, Sauk Centre, MN, 2008-2009

Directly supervised the land and forestry crews at CVM, a 500 acre organic farm that shares the work and property with individuals that have special needs to include autism and down syndrome. House manager responsible for residents, budget, maintenance and meals. Planned and prepared community meals for a village of over 50. Instructor for the print and paper making studio. Member of the Environmental and Sustainability Board.

Property Manager

U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, MED, Duluth, MN, 2005-2008

Property manager responsible for equipment and vehicles valued at over \$14 million. Purchasing officer for laboratory equipment and supplies. Payroll and travel manager for the Mid-Continent Ecology Division.

Operations Staff Officer

Battalion Operations, 3-67 Armor Regiment, 4th Infantry Division, Fort Hood, TX, 2004-2005

Forecast, identify, develop, plan and implement operations and training events including security, weapons qualification, logistics and travel for over 900 government personnel. Write operations orders, compile training schedules and delegate tasks to subordinates as well as other internal departments.

Executive Officer

C Company, 3-67 Armor Regiment, 4th Infantry Division, Fort Hood, TX, 2004

Second in command of 65 staff members, 14 military vehicles, weapons and equipment valued at over \$95 million. Maintenance and Supply Officer in charge of planning, administering, purchasing, scheduling and monitoring of inventories and maintenance.

Platoon Leader

B Company, 3-67 Armor Regiment, 4th Infantry Division, Fort Hood, TX, 2002-2004

Directly supervised a staff of 20 personnel in day-to-day operations to include security, traffic control points and combat missions during Operation Iraqi Freedom. Responsible and signed for equipment valued at \$28 million.

Community Support Specialist

Catholic Charities, Madison, WI, 1999-2001

Directly supporting and developing life skills for clients who have received a traumatic brain injury. Liaison for the community and our clients to include employment and therapy.